Jay Pitkänen, Content Marketing Strategist

+358407489055 - jay@ratracemaverick.com - linkedin.com/in/jaypitkanen/

Marketing Strategist with 7+ years experience turning business goals into actionable marketing initiatives. Using state of the art tools and technologies, I create +ROI campaigns to solve business problems while staying budget conscious.

Skills / Keywords

Python 3, Django, Python modules, JS, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, MySQL (MariaDB), Amazon RDS, Git, Github, JIRA, Trello, Asana, Slack, Ubuntu/Debian, Nginx, Docker, AWS, Heroku, Vercel, Pythonanywhere, Wordpress, Thrive Themes, Elementor, Elegant Themes, Generatepress, cPanel, Shared hosting, Local, Jarvis, IFTTT, Zapier, Airtable, Canva, GIMP, SEO, Marketing strategy, Email automation, Product launches, Sales funnel design, Facebook ads, Google ads, Instagram ads, Copywriting, CRO, Landing pages, Clickfunnels design, Conversion focused blog article writing, Blog strategy, Youtube video scripting

Professional Experience

July 2019 - Current | Remote Marketing Strategist

RRM Consulting

Web development and marketing consultation for coaches and course providers.

- Migrated client from expensive and ill-equipped CMS (content management system) saving time and money (60+h/mo, \$3000/yr)
- Revised client marketing strategy for immediate 10% increase in ROA and possibility to scale
- Solved 300+ tech support tickets regarding marketing software, online teaching platforms, email automation, sales platforms, etc.
- Created marketing strategy to grow \$8M company to \$20M within 3 years
- Content marketing strategy and roadmap for dozens of small business owners to increase lead generation and sales
- Created 40+ Wordpress blog websites for coaches and service providers
- Researched and wrote positive ROI SEO blog articles and coached business owners on writing their own articles
- Set up countless shared hosting (Namecheap, Siteground, WPX Hosting) for clients
- Wrote Python scripts for web scraping (BeautifulSoup) and automation (Selenium)

September 2017 - July 2019 | Remote

Marketing Manager

Attract With Your Energy

Marketing manager and frontend developer for relationship coaching company.

- Blog editor: wrote weekly conversion focused coaching article for lead generation
- Created IT infrastructure to make 20+ weekly coaching sessions possible in a fully remote company travelling constantly
- Website development and paid membership site design for a clientbase of 1500 people
- Social media management of Facebook group with over 3000 active members

- Built and launched 5-figure online course product on Wordpress-based Thrive Apprentice and actively provided technical support for userbase
- Created marketing strategy and roadmap to grow company from \$150k to \$600k in 4 years

September 2015 - June 2017 | Remote

Content Marketer

Thrive Themes

Copywriting, sales funnels, landing pages, product design, product launches, data analysis, A/B testing, data driven blog content for Wordpress software development company.

- Wrote weekly data-driven SEO (Search Engine Optimized) articles for the Thrive Themes blog, many reaching 14000 shares and over 3000% ROI
- Recruited and lead training and development of 6 new content marketing writers
- Copywriting for landing pages, review pages and direct sales pages
- Created web content, email chains and sales funnels for multiple 6-figure product launches
- Owned main support channel for product affiliates, increased affiliate revenue by 10%
- Created 3-month internship program in Lisbon, including accommodation and catering for the duration

June 2012 - January 2015 | Helsinki, Finland

HR Assistant

ISS Palvelut Oy

Training, event planning, management of company vehicles, employee relations for security division of the facility management company with 120 employees.

- Assisted HR team to reduce yearly vehicle fleet maintenance costs by over \$15K with safe driving-training events
- Reworked new-hire orientation program to include HR information and company resources
- Assisted HR team to create morale-boosting incentive programs that increased employee satisfaction and productivity
- Worked closely with security staff to learn of daily issues that cause stress and reduce performance

Education

2006 - 2010

Aalto University School of Business

Languages

Finnish (Native) **English** (Native) **French** (Conversational)

Courses and Related Skills

- freecodecamp.org Python, Javascript, Node.js, and Django
- Pink Shark PR Weekend Course Learned influencer marketing and public image management
- Kyle Cease Meditation Retreat Learned acceptance, mindfulness, meditation and self-healing
- Smartblogger.com Course 6-month course to build a blog and collect 1000 subscribers
- authorityhacker.com Website business course, built and sold website incaseofcamping.com for \$6k after 10 months
- milesbeckler.com Youtube channel building course. Built channel Enigmatic Man and website enigmaticman.com with a 60-day video publishing challenge